Daniel Molina-Power

San Tan Valley, AZ 85143

Phone: (480)800-7959 | Email:danielmolinapower@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-molina-power

GitHub: https://github.com/Dmolina-power Portfolio: https://danielmolinacodes.com

SUMMARY

Originally raised in Miami by an Artistic family, not able to escape the heat, driven to Arizona. Growing up sounded by the pop art in Miami I have developed a deep passion for style. To fulfill my passion of creating a more beautiful world I have become a Full-Stack Developer via the University of Arizona. Using my talents, in React, Node and JavaScript to create dynamic UX and UI experiences. Currently enrolled in UX Design certificate course with Google

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Html 5, CSS 3, JavaScript, SQL.

Applications: NodeJs

Libraries: React, BootStrap, Materialize, Foundation, Firebase.

Databases: MongoDB, MYSQL, Firestore

PROJECTS

• **Employee Directory** | https://github.com/Dmolina-power/Employee-directory-react.git **Link to Deployed Project** | https://dmolina-power.github.io/Employee-directory-react/

This is an employee directory built with React. It breaks up the application's UI into components, manages components state, and responds to user events.

• **Fitness Tracker** | https://github.com/Dmolina-power/fitness-Tracker **Link to Deployed Project** |https://limitless-sea-51961.herokuapp.com/

View, Create, and track daily workouts.built with MongoDB, Node.js, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap.

Send Moods | https://github.com/Dmolina-power/Project2
Link to Deployed Project | https://project-2-mood-music.herokuapp.com/

A group project that was built with HTML Bootstrap, CSS, JavaScript, Handlebars, Sequelize, JQuery, Express, Passport, MySql2. Created with Three other WebDevs.

MY ROLES IN THIS PROJECT: setting up theme and layout throughout all pages,and maintaining all front end code.

EXPERIENCE

Instructor2021- CurrentPersevereEloy, AZ

At Persevere I'm an Instructor teaching Full Stack Web Development to Inmates at a Correctional Facility. In the facility Students don't have access to the Internet, everything is built in local development. Students are learning to build MERN Stacks. Curriculum is 12 Months long. Currently I have 7 students enrolled in class.

Forklift Operator **2019** – 2020 Chewy Inc Goodyear, AZ

Forklift operator in a distribution warehouse. Successfully managed to safely operate a forklift while efficiently keeping production levels up.

Correctional Officer 2016 – 2018 La Palma Correctional Facility

Started as a regular C.O. and in less than three months became a first responder to incidents that evolved in the facility. Transferable skills from this job are: can work in a high stressful situation, prioritize, and work in a team to distribute goals to get the task complete, and successfully muilti-task in a high demand workplace.

Elov. AZ

Key Accomplishments: Awarded life saving plaquer for my contribution in saving an inmate's life from a drug overdose using CPR and AED techniques.

Lead Security Officer 2016 – 2016 **Vet-Sec Security** Tucson, AZ

Became a Lead security officer in less than three months, Successfully supervised employees in the security field to ensure safety and expand customer service with clients related to complaints and diagnosing and resolving communication problems between security personnel and clients on site.

Site Supervisor **2008** – 2016 **Security Watch Group** Miami, FL

Successfully supervised employees in the security field to ensure safety and expand customer service with clients related to complaints and diagnosing and resolving communication problems between security personnel and clients on site.

Ability to train new hire employees, evaluate employee performance, and conduct individual and staff meetings. Execute new policy to staff in accordance to client and/or company.

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: University of Arizona, Chandler, AZ

A 13-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Certification: University of Arizona, Chandler, AZ

Certificate: Grow with Google/Coursera

Learn the foundations of UX design, including empathizing with users, building wireframes and prototypes, and conducting research to test your designs.

Certification: Coursera, Online